Guide to the Burdette Keeland Architectural Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Video Recordings, 1989-2000
  - Keeland Roast, February 1989 (Box 8, Videocassette 10)
  - Keeland, 40 Proof: Forty Years of Burdette Keeland, 70 minutes, April 4, 1996 (Box 8, Videocassette 11)
  - Burdette Keeland Memorial Service, May 31, 2000 (Box 8, Videocassette 12)
  - Keeland, Burdette Keeland, April, 1993 or 1994 (Box 8, Videocassette 13)
  - Keeland, Burdette Keeland, May 3, 1995 (Box 8, Videocassette 14)
  - Keeland, Burdette Keeland, April 29, 1997 (Box 8, Videocassette 15)
- Correspondence Files, 1931-1996
  During his life Keeland kept a number of files for letters, some of them overlapping in subject or date. This material has been consolidated in general correspondence files by date. Correspondence with notable architectural and professional figures has been transferred to specific files for those individuals. Other important series of correspondence include those with Keeland’s wife, Margaret Scott Keeland, former high school classmates, friends from the Army, and members of his immediate family.
  - Correspondence - General, 1951-1996
    - 1951-1959 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1961 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1968 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1975 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - 1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - 1981 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - 1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - 1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - 1986 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - 1988 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - 1990 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - 1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - 1992 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - 1993 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - 1994 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - 1995 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - 1996 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Jonathan Barnett, 1989-1993 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Peter Blake, 1956, 1966-1971 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Bill Caudill, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Craig Ellwood, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - John Entenza, 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Ulrich Franzen, 1960, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Buckminster Fuller, approximately 1956 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Douglas Haskell, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Gerald Hines, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Bill Hobby, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Lyndon Johnson, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Philip Johnson, 1960-1962, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Charles Moore, 1978, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Colin Rowe, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Paul Rudolph, 1964, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Stanley Tigerman, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Robert Venturi, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Louie Welch, 1964, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence - Wife, 1943-1947
    - Margie Scott, 1943–1947 (Box 9, Folder 55-74)
  - Correspondence - High School Friends, 1943-1994
    - 1965–1972, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Carolyn Cheesman, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Sam Holliday, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 77-80)
    - Howard Horne, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 81-85)
    - Ava McDaniel, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Bill Shields, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - Mary Lou Steel, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Hugh W. (Bill) Temple, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 89-90)
    - Louis Wagner, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Pat West, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Robert Woodruff, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 93-96)
  - Correspondence - Army Friends, 1945-1947
    - Patrick Bascio, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - Thomas Baker, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - R.E. Blakeney, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - R. J. DeMasi, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Gordon Hastings, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - R. J. Henneman, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - William James, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Paul Marracq, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1931-1946
    - Grandparents (Arnold), 1946 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Richard Arnold (uncle), 1931, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - B.W. Keeland (father), 1945 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Mrs. B.W. Keeland (mother), 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1940s
    - Envelopes with Keeland Addresses, 1940s (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Letters from Burdette Keeland, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Cards Received (Illness), 1940s (Box 9, Folder 111)
- Clippings, 1950s-1990s
  Keeland kept an extensive file of newspaper clippings about his career and other subjects of interest. These are stored in 30 folders arranged in chronological order. Oversized clippings are contained in Box 27.
  - UH College of Architecture, 1950s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1990s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - UH College of Architecture, 1990s (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Keeland Work, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Keeland Work, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Keeland Work, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Keeland Work, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Personal, 1950s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Philip Johnson, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 15-18)
  - Dominique de Menil, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Cultural, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - MFA Hundertwasser Exhibition, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Architecture, Professional, 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
  - Broadway Apartments, 1964, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Allen’s Landing Building, 1966-1977 (Box 10, Folder 25-26)
  - Fraud Incident, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Architecture, General, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Houston Architecture, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Blueprint Ball, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Exhibitions, Conferences, 1983-1995
  The “Why, Houston, Why?” exhibition was a major event at the University of Houston College of Architecture in the early 1980s. Keeland was a faculty sponsor of this student-produced exhibition about Houston, exhibited in 1984 at the American Center in Paris. He also helped produce or participated in several conferences and symposia about urban planning. This section contains files related to those subjects.
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 31-32)
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Planning, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 33-36)
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Photographs, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 38-39)
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Paris Trip, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 40-41)
  - Why, Houston, Why? Exhibition - Booklets, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - American Planning Association Conference, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 43-44)
  - AIA/ACSA Conference, Philadelphia, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Urban Planning Symposium, UH, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 46-53)
  - Monterrey Planning Conference, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 54-55)
  - Ten Years Out Exhibition, Yale, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 56-57)
- Architectural Projects, 1950-1998
  This group of materials relates to Keeland’s architectural practice and is comprised of project files, clippings, sketches, and some photographs.
  - Index of Keeland Projects, 1961-1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Keeland Job Numbers, 1962-1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Detail Sketch of Steel House, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bridges Residence Project, 1950-1952 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Winchell Studio - Clippings, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Carousel Shop, Sunset Blvd., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Photographs, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Spring Branch Savings & Loan Building, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Houck Office Building, Weslayan, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Jenard Gross Projects, 1957-1967 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Jenard Gross Projects - Clippings, 1958-1965 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Holmes-Willowbend Shops, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Essex-Houck Office Building, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Essex-Houck Office Building, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Essex-Houck Office Building, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Essex-Houck Office Building, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Houghton Residence - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Horne Beach House - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Allen’s Landing Building, 1966-1976 (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
  - Woodland Acres Church of Christ, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Independence Hall, 1972-1977 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Barkdull Townhouses - Contract, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Virginia Street Townhouses - Clippings, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Kipling Street Townhouses, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Keeland Residence remodel, Ferndale St., 1978 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - 4101 Greenbriar Office Building, 1980, 1993–1998 (Box 11, Folder 34-37)
  - 4141 Greenbriar Office Building project, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Sunrise/Delphi Project, Tucson, AZ, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 39-40)
  - B.W. Keeland Spec House, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Keeland Residence remodel, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Keeland Residence remodel, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Keeland Residence remodel, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - UH Law Center Addition, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 45-52)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., new gate, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Cedarvale Cemetery Project, Baytown, TX, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 54-55)
  - Kaplan Residence Addition, Denver Publicity, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Evergreen Cemetery Project, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Garrett Residence Remodel (Meyerland Parade), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 58-59)
  - Elliott Bay House, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Efrem Kurtz Headstone Project, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 61-65)
  - Efrem Kurtz Headstone Project - Photographs, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Pam and Taylor Hicks Monument Project, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Hill Residence, Wimberley, TX, 1996-1999 (Box 11, Folder 68-73)
  - General Notes for Working Drawings, undated (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Ideas, 1980s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 75-76)
- Architectural Projects - Photographs, 1950-1999
  Keeland documented his work with a photographic record. This section contains pictures of most of his projects, built and unbuilt.
  - Keeland Projects - Negatives, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Woods Office Building - Negatives, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Gas Station Project - Negatives, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Keeland House, Drummond St., 1950 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Kipling Apartments, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Winchell Studio construction, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Winchell Studio, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Winchell Studio, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Arnold Residence, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
  - Houck Office Building model, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Shields Office Building, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Shields Office Building model, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 13-15)
  - Malco Oil Offices, New Mexico, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Wells Design Addition, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 17-18)
  - Spring Branch Savings and Loan Building, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 19-21)
  - Flour Mill, Port au Prince, Haiti, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 22-23)
  - Bayou Apartments on Broadway, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - MFA Birds and Beasts Exhibition, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Pan Am Oil Building Addition, Hines, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Carter Weekend House, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 27-28)
  - Taylor Green Weekend House, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 29-30)
  - Barnstone/Keeland Offices, Capitol St., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - La Grange, TX, Motel Project, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Houghton Residence, La Grange, TX, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Horne Beach House, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - IBM Office Building, Beaumont, TX, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Bank of Texas Conference Room and Lounge, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Lander Weekend House, Lake LBJ, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Williams Beach House, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Allen’s Landing Building, 1966-1976 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Allen’s Landing Building, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Dr. Fitch Offices Remodel, Sunset Blvd., 1969 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - MFA Hundertwasser Exhibition, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Bank of Texas Lobby Kiosk, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 43-44)
  - Independence Hall, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 45-46)
  - 4101 Greenbriar Office Building construction, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - 4101 Greenbriar Office Building storm damage, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - 4101 Greenbriar Office Building - Negative, approximately 1973 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Virginia Street Townhouses, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 50-56)
  - Keeland Residence remodel, Ferndale St., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Kipling Street Townhouses, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 58-61)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., 1986 (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., kitchen, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Keeland Work and Virginia Street Area, 1990s (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - Keeland Beach House, Galveston, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Keeland at Meyerland House, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Hill Residence, Wimberley, TX, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 69-76)
  - Johnson Addition to TAMU Architecture Building, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous Projects, 1950s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 78)
- Photographs - Architecture and Professional, 1931-1990s
  The photographs in this section document aspects of Keeland’s professional life, including his involvement with the University of Houston College of Architecture and government and civic groups, such as the Park People and the Houston Planning Commission.
  - Kern Place Gateway, El Paso, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Boca Raton, FL, 1950s (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Houston Architecture, 1950s (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Keeland at Yale University, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Guitar-Lyons House, Abilene, TX, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Old Jeff Davis Hospital, Houston, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Seminar, Lake Travis, TX, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ant Farm, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - The Park People, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - City Planning Commission, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - College of Architecture Gala, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
  - Sesquicentennial Park Competition, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - AIA Sand Castle Competition, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Ricardo Legoretta Party, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Keeland Roast, UH, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Philip Johnson Visit, UH, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Getty Center Model, Los Angeles, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Kipling St. Apartments Demolition, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Unknown Event, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Architecture Photos, Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Photographs - Family and Friends, 1920s-2000
  Other photographs in the collection record Keeland’s personal life, including his childhood, his army service, family, and friends. A highlight of his army photos is a historic photograph of Frank Lloyd Wright’s Imperial Hotel in downtown Tokyo (1914-1968).
  - Keeland Portraits, 1950-2000 (Box 13, Folder 24-26)
  - B.W. Keeland, Sr., 1940s (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Army, Japan, Photographs, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 28-29)
  - Family Photographs, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 30-32)
  - Family Photographs - Margie Scott Keeland, 1920s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Family Photographs, 1950s (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Family Photographs, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Family Photographs - Negatives, 1950s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 36-37)
  - Family Photographs - Negatives, 1980s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Family Photographs, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Family Photographs, 1980s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Keeland Family Christmas, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Bridge Beach Club, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Keeland Family, Colorado, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Keeland Family, Galveston, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Family Card, undated (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Family Photographs, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 46-48)
  - Family Photographs - Negatives, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 49-50)
  - Family and Friends - Negatives, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Howard Barnstone, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Friends, 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 53-54)
  - Keeland and Tennis Friends, 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 55-58)
  - Keeland Birthday Party, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Keeland, Todd, and Wingfield, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Harwood Taylor Photograph, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 61)
- Harry Walker Photographs, 1900-1940s
  Keeland acquired through his wife a collection of photographic negatives owned by Harry Walker (1894-1971), husband of Carrie Scott Walker (1895-1981), Mrs. Keeland’s aunt. The negatives cover the period from the turn of the twentieth century to the 1940s and record Walker’s life growing up in Beaumont, Texas, and his adult life after his move to Houston in the late 1910s. Walker was apparently the photographer on most of the negatives. Although most of the subjects are unidentified, the pictures provide an important view of domestic life and dress during that era. Of interest are photographs of Walker’s home at 1914 Bissonnet, Houston, with views of the area that includes Poe Elementary School when the neighborhood was new in 1929. Historical views of Houston from the 1920s include Rice Institute, Hermann Hospital, the Houston Ship Channel, and the San Jacinto Trust Company, his employer. There are also historic images of pioneer aviatrix Katherine Stinson flying a Wright Brothers biplane about 1915. The names of the folders and the filing system are Walker’s, except that the Rice, Hermann, and Stinson photographs have been moved to separate folders. Another folder includes several photographs of downtown Houston in the snow, about 1925, with views of Union Station and nearby buildings.
  - Beaumont, approximately 1900-1920s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Friends, 1910s-1920s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Friends, 1910s-1920s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Navy, 1910s (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Trips, 1915-1920s (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Trips, 1915-1920s (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Trips, 1915-1920s (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Harry Walker Photographs, 1910s–1940s (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Harry Walker Photographs, 1910s–1940s (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Harry Walker Photographs, 1910s–1940s (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Harry Walker Photographs, 1910s–1940s (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Harry Walker Photographs, 1910s–1940s (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Carrie, 1910s-1920s (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Carrie, 1910s-1920s (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Children, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Family, 1920s-1940s (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Houston, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Home, 1929-1940s (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Personal, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Pets, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Sports, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Webster, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Scotts, approximately 1930 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Katherine Stinson, approximately 1915 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Wrecks, approximately 1916 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Rice, Hermann Hospital, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Mississippi, 1940s (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - San Jacinto Trust Co., 1920s (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - San Jacinto Trust Co., 1920s (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - San Jacinto Trust Co., 1920s (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Fords Lake Lumber Co., 1920 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Shipyard, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Oil Well Brazoria, 1940s (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Downtown Houston in Snow, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Planning Commission, 1913-1993
  Keeland was appointed to the Houston Planning Commission in 1964 by Mayor Louie Welch. In 1981 he became chairman and served in that capacity until he left the commission in 1991. During this time Houston experienced phenomenal growth, thus challenging the planning commission to find ways to respond to these pressures in a city without comprehensive zoning or other land use laws. During Keeland’s tenure on the commission, major issues included the city’s first tree ordinance, the controversial proposal to extend Chimney Rock Road across Buffalo Bayou, and the extensive study and preparation for the zoning referendum election of 1994, which ultimately was unsuccessful. As chairman Keeland was an advocate of land use planning and, in particular, the enactment of a city-wide zoning ordinance. His files reflect these issues and others. A number of the zoning reference materials relate to a Planning and Zoning Commission Workshop held at the Woodlands Conference Center in 1992.
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968, 1984-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Lists, 1969-1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1973-1985 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1985-1988 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974, 1984-1987 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Tree Ordinance - Reference, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Tree Ordinance - Regulations, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Tree Ordinance - Clippings, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Tree Ordinance - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Chimney Rock Extension, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Chimney Rock Extension - Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Clear Lake Streets Issue - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Brittmore-Tanner Business Park, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Zoning Issue - Clippings, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Zoning Issue - Reference, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Task Force on Planning, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Grand Parkway Materials, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Land Use Analysis, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Keeland Interview, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Planning Materials, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Sesquicentennial Park Brochure, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Planning and Zoning Commission Workshop, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 30-34)
  - Zoning Workbook, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - The Basics of Zoning by John Mixon, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Flexible Zoning: How it Works by ULI, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Houston Culture and History Profile, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    [Cataloged: F394.H8 C85 1992]
  - Zoning Documentary Committee, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Houston: Study of Parks and Greenspace, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    [Cataloged: SB483.H6 S78 1993]
  - Houston: Tentative Plans for its Development, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    [Cataloged: F394.H8 C65 1913a]
  - Report of the City Planning Commission, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Houston: Study Plan for 1990, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Houston: Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Houston: Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 45-46)
  - Houston: Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 47-48)